<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="3183" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:29:48.403" Score="177" ViewCount="164710" Body="&lt;p&gt;What are some of the rule changes that Pathfinder brings in comparison to D&amp;amp;D 3.5?  I am curious what changes were made so I can explain to my group what it has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="18" LastEditorUserId="33569" LastEditDate="2018-12-01T00:56:14.820" LastActivityDate="2018-12-01T00:56:14.820" Title="What are the primary differences between the rules of D&amp;D 3.5 and Pathfinder?" Tags="&lt;pathfinder-1e&gt;&lt;dnd-3.5e&gt;&lt;edition-comparison&gt;" AnswerCount="6" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="65" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 4.0" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="9" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:30:19.027" Score="52" ViewCount="31128" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am currently a player in a D&amp;amp;D 3.5 game where rolling a 1 on any attack roll is not only an automatic miss, but also means that something &quot;bad&quot; happens – such as dropping your sword, falling over prone, etc. The DM insists that this is part of the core rules, but I cannot find a reference to it anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is the Natural 1 Epic Failure an actual official rule, or just a house rule that my DM forgot was a house rule?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="19" LastEditorUserId="1204" LastEditorDisplayName="anon186" LastEditDate="2015-02-03T08:34:10.427" LastActivityDate="2020-08-10T21:16:03.780" Title="Is a fumble on a natural 1 an official rule?" Tags="&lt;dnd-3.5e&gt;&lt;fumbles&gt;" AnswerCount="12" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:30:54.283" Score="30" ViewCount="19166" Body="&lt;p&gt;Many RPGs are extremely complex and hard for first time gamers to get into.  Many others assume (even to the point of saying so in their introduction) that they are for people who already know what a roleplaying game is. Or they are organized more like an encyclopedia of options instead of walking prospective players through the steps needed to get started playing the game. These games can intimidate and turn off new gamers trying to learn the hobby.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obviously people get into the hobby using a variety of games, usually because someone experienced will help them through the learning curve.  However, I'm interested in games that are specifically beginner friendly - that have this as a stated goal and/or do a really good job of being someone's first RPG. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Please answer keeping in mind the &lt;a href=&quot;https://rpg.meta.stackexchange.com/questions/1070/are-game-recommendation-questions-disallowed-on-rpg-se&quot;&gt;site guidelines for system-recommendation questions&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="33" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-03-16T15:45:25.800" LastActivityDate="2016-02-26T10:14:56.533" Title="What are the most beginner friendly table top role playing games?" Tags="&lt;game-recommendation&gt;" AnswerCount="7" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="8" ClosedDate="2013-04-07T04:20:11.610" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="34" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:31:59.507" Score="24" ViewCount="4241" Body="&lt;p&gt;What are the official Wizards of the Coast / TSR D&amp;amp;D campaign settings?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ones I know of off hand are the following, also it would be good to know what rule edition they initially started in and if they are no longer updated as of what edition:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Forgotten Realms&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dragonlance&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eberron&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greyhawk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastEditorUserId="52533" LastEditDate="2019-09-06T04:05:35.790" LastActivityDate="2021-03-19T00:14:19.960" Title="What is the full list of official D&amp;D settings?" Tags="&lt;dungeons-and-dragons&gt;&lt;campaign-settings&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" CommunityOwnedDate="2010-08-20T14:56:21.283" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 4.0" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:32:29.257" Score="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;Multiclassing no longer takes an XP hit, and your favored class gives you one of two bonuses at every level:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;+1 hp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;+1 skill point&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Advanced Players Guide add other options for specific Race/Class combos&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="39" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:32:29.257" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="28" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:34:14.290" Score="22" ViewCount="606" Body="&lt;p&gt;For example, if an NPC escalates conflict to gunfight, but my PC does not want to shoot him and tries to resolve situation by just talking while evading shots - can he not escalate and not roll dice for acuity+will, and consequently, still inflict talking fallout instead of gunfight fallout to NPC?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="26" LastEditorDisplayName="anon186" LastEditDate="2010-09-04T15:16:36.677" LastActivityDate="2010-09-04T15:16:36.677" Title="Can characters in Dogs in the Vineyard have different escalation levels in conflict?" Tags="&lt;dogs-in-the-vineyard&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:34:31.870" Score="25" Body="&lt;p&gt;There's a fairly large smattering of stuff. Here's a taste:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Races have all been powered up; +2 to two stats, -2 to one stat (including half-orcs!), with some different abilities for some. In 3.5 terms, they're roughly an ECL of +1 (as opposed to 0 in 3e).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No one has a favored class decided by their race now - you choose your favored class, typically the one you level at 1st level, but you don't get an XP penalty for multiclassing too high above that one - you just gain an extra skill point or hit point for leveling your favored class.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many of the classes have had options added, often to fill out &quot;dead levels.&quot; Barbarians gain extra &quot;rage powers,&quot; sorcerers have bloodlines that give them granted powers, wizards have varying effects for specializing, fighters get more than just bonus feats, undead-turning is actually energy channeling and also results in an AOE heal, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Classes have some sort of awesome power at 20th level, encouraging single-classing as a valid option.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Complex combat maneuvers and defenses against them have been boiled down to two numbers: Combat Maneuver Attack bonus and Combat Maneuver Defense.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="13" LastEditorUserId="264" LastEditDate="2015-04-15T04:03:27.357" LastActivityDate="2015-04-15T04:03:27.357" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:34:44.883" Score="30" Body="&lt;p&gt;In 3rd edition this was not an official rule, but a very common house rule.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If it was added in 3.5 I'd be surprised, as this is not a very &quot;fun&quot; rule unless you have a group who enjoys the humor of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following item has a rule set for this house rule.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myth-weavers.com/showthread.php?t=26674&quot;&gt;http://www.myth-weavers.com/showthread.php?t=26674&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:34:44.883" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="302" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:34:54.757" Score="15" ViewCount="4743" Body="&lt;p&gt;The players in my Greyhawk campaign are about to enter the Bright Desert, and I'd like to use some desert-specific random encounter tables — does anyone have anything suitable? Edition is irrelevant, since I can always convert. Game system is also pretty irrelevant although I probably want fantasy tables.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastEditorUserId="321" LastEditDate="2010-11-05T19:12:20.613" LastActivityDate="2019-08-27T14:43:22.033" Title="Where can I find desert random encounter tables?" Tags="&lt;dungeons-and-dragons&gt;&lt;encounter-tables&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" ClosedDate="2019-08-27T16:06:46.310" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="13" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:35:44.397" Score="54" ViewCount="123802" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have complaints from someone in one of my groups that the 3.5 monk isn't good for anything offensive, only for defense and disarming (defenestration wasn't mentioned).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My experience has only been with a monk in the party, and she constantly fought defensively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do we make this character brokenly good?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="35" LastEditorUserId="33569" LastEditDate="2021-11-08T22:05:20.430" LastActivityDate="2022-02-17T18:48:42.233" Title="How can we optimize a monk (especially for offense)?" Tags="&lt;dnd-3.5e&gt;&lt;optimization&gt;&lt;monk&gt;" AnswerCount="13" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="15" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 4.0" />
  <row Id="14" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:35:55.627" Score="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;The only official ruling I can recall in any core D&amp;amp;D ruleset is that it's an automatic failure. Making it some sort of epic failure is typically up to the DM.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="13" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:35:55.627" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="15" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="24" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:36:06.783" Score="13" ViewCount="870" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm looking for the name of a small, indie RPG that I came across a while ago. The game used tarot-like cards instead of dice. When something in the game needed to be decided, then cards were drawn and the results interpreted. I remember the game dealing with a lot of abstract concepts and archtypes. Can anyone direct me to the name of this particular game?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="19" LastEditorUserId="321" LastEditDate="2012-06-24T17:10:41.203" LastActivityDate="2012-06-25T05:56:41.933" Title="Seeking Name of Abstract, Card-Based RPG" Tags="&lt;indie-rpg&gt;&lt;product-identification&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="16" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:36:43.957" Score="41" ViewCount="3276" Body="&lt;p&gt;Having recently moved most of the way across the US, I am looking for effective ways to continue to game with roleplayers from my previous home.  What tools (Skype, mapping applications, etc.) and strategies (techincal: sound, lighting, etc. or game-oriented: rule changes, etc.) have players found helped to ease the strangeness of playing without everyone being at the same table?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="37" LastEditorUserId="140" LastEditorDisplayName="anon186" LastEditDate="2012-01-18T05:57:46.323" LastActivityDate="2015-08-05T12:34:04.607" Title="What tools or strategies have you found useful when not all players can be in the same physical space?" Tags="&lt;tools&gt;&lt;remote&gt;" AnswerCount="16" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="16" ClosedDate="2016-04-04T07:02:15.770" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="18" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="330" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:37:50.537" Score="13" ViewCount="5485" Body="&lt;p&gt;Is normal (feat-based) multi-classing beneficial in D&amp;amp;D 4e?  Is there a better way to achieve the same character design (a character with facets of two classes)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="45" LastEditorUserId="53" LastEditDate="2010-08-19T19:50:10.727" LastActivityDate="2011-04-13T03:24:16.817" Title="Advantage to normal multiclassing in D&amp;D4?" Tags="&lt;dnd-4e&gt;&lt;multi-classing&gt;" AnswerCount="10" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="19" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="72" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:37:53.923" Score="11" ViewCount="383" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've stepped up to run one of the local Encounters tables for this season.  However I don't have adventure chapters 1 &amp;amp; 2.  What has happened in the story up until now?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="53" LastEditorUserId="1204" LastEditDate="2018-11-14T11:50:05.037" LastActivityDate="2018-11-14T11:50:05.037" Title="D&amp;D Encounters Dark Sun Season" Tags="&lt;dnd-4e&gt;&lt;dark-sun&gt;&lt;dnd-encounters&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="21" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:38:44.200" Score="6" ViewCount="2874" Body="&lt;p&gt;Aside from &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://knowdirectionpodcast.com/category/podcasts/35-private-sanctuary/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;3.5 Private Sanctuary&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, are there any other podcasts that regularly cover the 3.5 or d20 system?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="19" LastEditorUserId="31589" LastEditDate="2017-03-22T17:46:03.420" LastActivityDate="2017-03-22T17:46:03.420" Title="D&amp;D 3.5 Podcasts" Tags="&lt;dnd-3.5e&gt;&lt;podcast&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" ClosedDate="2017-03-22T19:02:09.040" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="23" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="10" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:39:26.540" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;I like this one, that I use on occasion: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.d20pfsrd.com/extras/community-creations/house-rules/random-encounters/terrain/desert&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;‎Jreyst's desert terrain random encounter table&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="698" LastEditorUserId="321" LastEditDate="2010-11-05T17:46:42.083" LastActivityDate="2010-11-05T17:46:42.083" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="24" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="15" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:39:42.327" Score="23" Body="&lt;p&gt;Sounds like &quot;Everway,&quot; which came out in the mid-1990s from Wizards of the Coast.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="50" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:39:42.327" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="25" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="18" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:39:46.103" Score="1" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've only ever used it to get that one feat or ability I want for my main class, such as a rogue multiclassing into ranger for the regular one handed as offhand. or to get a familar by multiclassing into an arcane class.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="39" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:39:46.103" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="27" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="82" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:41:30.327" Score="13" ViewCount="558" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've been writing an encounter with fire beetles in a sewer.  I need a good monster to complement them while keeping it at a level 1 or 2 encounter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="53" LastEditorUserId="321" LastEditDate="2010-10-04T19:38:47.410" LastActivityDate="2010-10-04T19:56:06.100" Title="Monster Complement for Fire Beetles" Tags="&lt;dnd-4e&gt;&lt;encounters&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="0" ClosedDate="2021-08-26T14:00:31.110" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="28" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="7" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:41:46.877" Score="19" Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, a character in Dogs in the Vineyard can choose not to escalate at the same time as an NPC. PCs don't escalate until they do something escalate-y.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, fallout dice are determined by the action being done, not the current escalation level. If you've escalated to shooting, but you're trying to talk someone down this turn, you only inflict talking fallout.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="62" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:41:46.877" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="29" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="21380" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:42:13.227" Score="21" ViewCount="7849" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've been playing since the system was released. I've been a fan of the design changes, except the loot. I loved random loot that allowed my players to be surprised by something awesome, and then again by something equally awful. But at least they could sell it. With 4e, I've been varying between just giving items and upgrades to items as &quot;rewards&quot; and also just giving the loot parcels whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I come from a 3.5 background and have found that the players' ability to use random loot they thought was useless allowed for entertaining sessions. I also understand that 4.0 characters require a certain amount of magic items to be successful. How can I give the characters the magic items they need to be successful, but also make it feel random, and allow for fun items to be used in creative ways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastEditorUserId="140" LastEditDate="2014-04-24T15:50:49.367" LastActivityDate="2016-01-22T20:09:17.680" Title="How do current D&amp;D 4e DMs deal with loot?" Tags="&lt;dnd-4e&gt;&lt;treasure&gt;" AnswerCount="13" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="4" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="31" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="1833" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:42:22.990" Score="26" ViewCount="2345" Body="&lt;p&gt;Generally if PCs run from a fight, I would give the monsters a free attack, and then let the PCs escape automatically (playing 1e/0e D&amp;amp;D). Of course if they linger around, the monsters may come back later. I have read that in 3e/4e, &quot;retreating from an enemy with the same speed as you is suicide; he will always be able to match your speed and end up adjacent to you&quot; (see link below). I would like to find some middle ground. I am thinking of perhaps a table which could be rolled on every round of a chase, until the person being chased either gets away, gets hit in the back, or re-engages in melee. Any ideas?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roleplayingtips.com/readissue.php?number=482&quot;&gt;http://www.roleplayingtips.com/readissue.php?number=482&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;See section &quot;Nullify The Disadvantages Of Retreating&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="27" LastEditorDisplayName="anon186" LastEditDate="2010-09-18T21:45:36.540" LastActivityDate="2018-10-19T01:26:10.973" Title="How do you adjudicate a chase?" Tags="&lt;dungeons-and-dragons&gt;" AnswerCount="11" CommentCount="3" FavoriteCount="1" ClosedDate="2018-10-25T04:12:58.120" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="32" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="18" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:42:43.723" Score="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;It's certainly not as beneficial as in past systems, such as in 3.5 where it was virtually mandatory, especially if you wanted to qualify for a prestige class (many seemed to &lt;em&gt;require&lt;/em&gt; multiclassing).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is one class that benefits from it greatly - bards, with their Jack-of-all-trades nature, can multiclass via multiclassing feats into multiple primary classes, picking up powers from many sources if they wish. There's actually a PDF supplement on D&amp;amp;D Insider - not one that requires a subscription, if I recall correctly - that offers alternate paragon paths and epic destinies for bards who choose to multiclass in certain ways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="13" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:42:43.723" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="34" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:43:26.937" Score="28" Body="&lt;p&gt;Well, if we're only counting the WotC ones, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dark Sun -- 3.x material in Dragon and Dungeon, and of course it just came out for 4e.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eberron -- winner of the setting&#xA;search, by Keith Baker. Got a lot of&#xA;WotC support.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Forgotten Realms -- the&#xA;biggest one, probably.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ghostwalk -- one book, interesting setting about undead.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greyhawk --&#xA;lightly supported by WotC, but don't forget that WotC's organized play was mostly&#xA;about Greyhawk!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mahasarpa -- Web only, Southeast Asia flavored.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nentir Vale (aka Points of Light) -- the default 4e setting.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Planescape -- got mostly magazine support from WotC. Built into the 4e generic setting.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ravenloft -- will be an official 4e setting next year, I think.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rokugan -- yeah, Legends of the Five Rings. WotC published a version of Oriental Adventures using the setting, though.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spelljammer -- showed up in Dungeon magazine once or twice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mystara - Basic D&amp;amp;D &amp;quot;Known World&amp;quot; -- Showed up at least in the 30th anniversary Dragon mag and maybe a few others.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Settings introduced for 5th Edition:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ravnica -- a &lt;em&gt;Magic the Gathering&lt;/em&gt; setting published in &lt;em&gt;Guildmaster's Guide to Ravnica&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wildemount, in the world of Exandria -- The setting of &lt;em&gt;Critical Role: Campaign 2&lt;/em&gt;, published in &lt;em&gt;Explorer's Guide to Wildemount&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Theros -- a &lt;em&gt;Magic the Gathering&lt;/em&gt; setting published in &lt;em&gt;Mythic Odysseys of Theros&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TSR ones also include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Blackmoor - The Original setting, different from the &amp;quot;Blackmoor&amp;quot; in Mystara&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Al-Qadim - Arabian knights&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Birthright - PCs rule countries&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Council of Wyrms - dragon PCs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dragonlance - based on the novels&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jakandor - island mini-setting&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pelinore - from Imagine magazine&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I'm not counting the various subregions of the Forgotten Realms, like Maztica. I'm also not listing all the third party settings. Lots of those!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dungeons_%26_Dragons_campaign_settings&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;A full list can also be found on Wikipedia.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastEditorUserId="33569" LastEditDate="2021-03-19T00:14:19.960" LastActivityDate="2021-03-19T00:14:19.960" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 4.0" />
  <row Id="38" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="31" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:45:30.707" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Personally, I use opposed initiative rolls to slightly increase and decrease either parties' rate of movement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="25" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:45:30.707" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="39" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="1733" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:45:47.350" Score="53" ViewCount="22220" Body="&lt;p&gt;If someone doesn't have any fudge dice, what are the best methods to replace them and why?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Term: Fudge Dice are six sided dice with two sides labeled with a +, two sides with a -, and two sides that are blank.  They are usually rolled in groups of four, and the + and - sides are added together to get a number between -4 and +4, with positive usually being better.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="66" LastEditorUserId="66" LastEditDate="2010-08-27T18:35:25.483" LastActivityDate="2021-02-01T15:56:58.370" Title="What can I use in place of Fudge Dice?" Tags="&lt;dice&gt;&lt;fudge&gt;&lt;fate&gt;" AnswerCount="28" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="6" ClosedDate="2015-12-02T16:04:46.063" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="41" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:47:00.983" Score="12" Body="&lt;p&gt;From what I can find, 3.5 lists a 1 as an automatic miss with no other options, but it's a popular house rule. (It does, like everything, require a &quot;good&quot; DM. Bad use of critical fumbles is an easy way to piss off your players. And not in a good way)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="42" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:47:00.983" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="42" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="39" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:47:23.963" Score="18" Body="&lt;p&gt;Fudge dice have (as best as I can remember) two pluses, two minuses, and two blanks, right? Why not just use a normal d6 and make, say, 1-2 &quot;plus,&quot; 3-4 &quot;minus,&quot; and 5-6 &quot;blank?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="13" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:47:23.963" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="43" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="66" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:47:24.353" Score="13" ViewCount="1006" Body="&lt;p&gt;When playing Hero System, experienced players can really get the most out of every point, and create incredible characters, while new players can find the system a little overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How do you deal with this discrepancy when integrating new player into your group, who aren't familiar with Hero System?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="25" LastActivityDate="2010-08-26T00:55:09.407" Title="Dealing With Inexperienced Players in Hero System" Tags="&lt;hero-system&gt;&lt;new-players&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="44" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="39" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:48:34.537" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;The basic math is that you'll get a -1 33% of the time, a 0 33% of the time, and a +1 33% of the time. You can always just roll standard six siders: 1-2 is a -1, 3-4 is a 0, and 5-6 is a +1. Or if you're willing to mark up your dice and you have dice with pips on them, use a marker to turn the 2 and the 3 into a &quot;-&quot; sign; the 4 and the 5 into a &quot;+&quot; sign; and the 1 and the 6 into a &quot;0&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:48:34.537" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="45" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="89" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:48:39.310" Score="25" ViewCount="2414" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have a character that I want to develop slowly through the campaign.  By this I mean I want him to slowly mature and change his personality through the sessions.  What tool or trick can I use to keep myself on track when roleplaying him?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="45" LastEditorUserId="52137" LastEditDate="2019-10-13T15:43:25.330" LastActivityDate="2019-10-14T02:25:06.290" Title="What are some character development tools?" Tags="&lt;roleplaying&gt;&lt;tools&gt;&lt;character-development&gt;" AnswerCount="6" CommentCount="0" FavoriteCount="5" ClosedDate="2019-10-14T06:42:31.063" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="46" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="61" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:48:44.990" Score="13" ViewCount="1274" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've run around 8 encounters with a shaman and his spirit, and many questions about it's properties have been raised.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is the spirit unsubstantial?  Does the spirit float?  The spirit is supposedly anything the character wants it to be so if they pick an eagle can it fly and attack things hanging onto the ceiling etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does anyone know of any relevant rules? Have any of you encountered these issues? What were your rulings?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="53" LastEditorDisplayName="anon186" LastEditDate="2010-10-25T17:55:37.840" LastActivityDate="2010-10-25T17:55:37.840" Title="What are the properties of Shaman Spirit?" Tags="&lt;dnd-4e&gt;&lt;shaman&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="47" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:48:58.310" Score="12" ViewCount="360" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am looking for players to join a play-by-chat game. I have set up a wiki for the game at Obsidian Portal, and have advertised on a couple Yahoo Groups dedicated to gaming. Are there any other places to advertise that would get some good results? Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="70" LastActivityDate="2010-11-10T17:44:47.837" Title="What are the best places on the Web to advertise for players?" Tags="&lt;new-players&gt;" AnswerCount="8" CommentCount="1" FavoriteCount="1" ClosedDate="2012-02-29T16:08:31.183" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="49" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="31" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:49:11.710" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;I think if you're giving your players encounters they regularly cannot win, it isn't meeting the current goal of 4.0. The players should always feel powerful. Of course it's always good to let them know that something scary is out there waiting for them, but not often enough that you should probably be inventing a &quot;runaway&quot; table.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, I often feel the desire to run a particularly deadly and fearful campaign. In cases like this, it may be better to give your players tools in order to escape. If you have a particularly dangerous world, try and think about how the world has dealt with these dangers in general. Perhaps powders or traps that the players have a certain number of that they can throw at the monsters as they run away. Invent items that will assist them, as that's likely what would happen in a world so dangerous that the heroes are often running away.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="48" LastActivityDate="2010-08-19T19:49:11.710" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
  <row Id="50" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="128" CreationDate="2010-08-19T19:49:38.950" Score="36" ViewCount="10268" Body="&lt;p&gt;What are some strategies that I can employ to handle a power gamer that constantly outshines the rest of the party? This is a friend of us all and we don't want to boot him, but combat simply isn't fun when the party has nothing to do while he mops up an encounter by himself.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="19" LastEditorDisplayName="user8248" LastEditDate="2013-11-21T04:54:26.073" LastActivityDate="2015-01-10T07:09:04.957" Title="How to Handle a Powergamer / Munchkin" Tags="&lt;gm-techniques&gt;&lt;problem-players&gt;&lt;powergaming&gt;" AnswerCount="15" CommentCount="2" FavoriteCount="5" ClosedDate="2015-01-10T15:50:59.090" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 2.5" />
</posts>